How's it going everyone? In this video,
I'm going to cover how to trade candle
3. With this video completed, you will
now have a video on how to trade candle
2, three, and four, or each candle
within my fractal model. Let's get into
the video. Now, the main thing you want
to understand is wick size with candles.
We want to be trading expansion candles
which have small wicks that support
expansion. You can see we make a small
wick or an open low and then we have a
one-sided directional move which is an
expansion. And over here if we have a
reversal candle that has a large wick so
that doesn't support expansion and see
we open we have a large opposing run
then we move back towards our opening
price and close. So our whole thing is
we want to trade following reversal
candles when we are trading candle 3. So
here you can see if we had a small wick
that is when we could look to trade
candle 2 when supported by a change in
the state of delivery on the lower time
frame. But with a large wick like this
I'm going to want to let this candle
close. You can see once this candle
closes back inside of the range of its
previous we have a large wick which
doesn't support expansion during this
given time frame. So, we would want to
wait for the open of the next candle or
candle 3 to get on side with this
expansion lower. So, what does this look
like on the lower time frames? You can
see we have that large wick which
doesn't support expansion. And what do I
mean by that? Price isn't trending in
one direction. It opens and closes in
relatively the same point. So, the first
thing I'm going to look for is from this
high, do I have a change in the state of
delivery? I do. So, now this confirms
the reversal or that candle 2 has
reversed. So then I can look for a
continuation in candle 3. So how am I
going to do that? Well, you can look for
any sort of entry model in here. But
ideally, I'm going to want to let the
wick form and then trade the body lower.
So what does that look like? I
personally wait for continuation order
blocks. You can see price opens, sweeps
out a high or into a point of interest,
has an opposing candle formation,
confirming that this wick has been
created on the higher time frame, and
then I can anticipate price to continue
lower from that point. So, just to
review, if I have a small wick in candle
2, that is when I can look to trade
candle 2 as it supports expansion lower.
When I have a large wick or a large
opposing run from candle 2's opening
price, that is when I'm going to want to
let that candle close and then look to
trade candle 3. And that is because
we've already used a lot of range in
candle 2. If you've noticed in candle 2
here and in candle 3, price moves
relatively the same distance. It's just
in candle three, it's spending half of
that time going up and half of it going
down. Versus in candle 3, it is a
one-sided move. So that is what we are
focusing on capturing in candle 3 is
that continuation following a candle 2
reversal. We're not really going to want
to focus on trading candle 3 when we
have a candle 2 expansion because that
is when we can get caught in a new phase
of price. So let's hop into a few
examples in Trading View. So here we are
with our first example and it is on
EuroUSD on the daily chart. Now if you
take a look we have expansion down
taking out lows and then we have
expansion met with an expansion which is
a reversal. Then we have price retracing
into a fair value gap and you notice
that this daily candle is a reversal
candle. price has not yet expanded
within this current day versus if you
look down here we also have a candle 2
closure but price expands and you can
see how that can set up a consolidation
as price goes from expansion into
consolidation so with the expansion into
consolidation and then viewing this as a
reversal I'm looking for price to expand
higher in the next day let's drop down
to the 1 hour time frame so here we are
on the 1 hour time frame and you can see
we are now looking to trade candle three
or the third day in a swing on the daily
time frame. And so what I'm going to
want to look for now is that
continuation. You can see we do have
price reaching into a fair value gap
here. Let's see if we can get a
continuation from this point of interest
to trade it higher.
As we let this play out, you can see we
failed to close over that level, which
means that we want to see a new low made
to form a new protected swing. So
marking out the new low. Now, where is
our series of down close candles? Right
there. Let's see if we can get a close
over that.
And there we get the close over. So,
then I could take a long setup on the
open of this new candle, my stop on the
protected low, and look for 2 R or for
those projections above. So, let's see
what happened
here. You can see we got a retest of
that level, a new swing point, and then
we traded to that high. So, just to
review, why is this a good candidate to
trade candle 3? Well, look at candle 2.
We have a nice reversal candle. Price
opens, trades lower pretty aggressively,
and that is met with an aggressive move
higher closing relatively around the
same point. So, forming a reversal on
this day or a Tuesday reversal. Then,
I'm going to look to trade that
continuation on Wednesday cuz
continuations are easier to trade. So,
let's get into another example. So here
we are in another example and if you
take a look at this closure here we'll
let another candle print. We have a nice
bearish closure. You see how that is a
nice reversal candle and what do we
notice? We have a change in the state of
delivery on the lower time frame. That
means we can be looking for
continuations lower in this next candle.
In this case it's the hourly instead of
the daily. And so instead of using the
hourly as the lower time frame I'll be
using the 5minut. Now marking this up
what do we have? We have a fair value
gap right here. Price reaches into it
and does what? Closes below the up close
candle there. So this is where I could
then look to take an entry on the open.
I have a protected swing and then I
could look for 2 R or to look towards
those projections that line up with the
liquidity resting below.
So what do we get? We get a move lower.
And do we go take out those lows? We do.
And it takes a minute, but we do get
there. So the main thing to review here
is we have a nice reversal candle which
sets up a continuation candle. So that
is what I want you to take away from
this example is focus on those candle
twos that have a nice reversal candle.
Don't try to trade candle twos that
expand a ton because that is when you
can get caught in a retracement, a
consolidation, or a reversal. So here we
are in our next example and I'll show
you what a less than ideal but still a
tradable setup looks like. You can see
here we do have the 4our forming a
reversal candle, right? And it is very
bearish. So we could anticipate price to
trade lower towards previous day low.
And if we take a look here on the 30
minute, we have a protected swing right
here as price has closed below this
level after reaching to fair value gaps.
And then we get a retracement back up.
So with this closure here, what do we
notice? There is a small wick. So it's
actually tradable within candle 2. So,
if we drop down to the 3minut time frame
here and take a look at it, you'll
notice that if you wanted to when paired
with SMT here, you could look to trade
this reversal here. But let's say I
wanted to look to trade the
continuation. What would that look like?
Now, normally I'm looking for a order
block to form within that new higher
time frame candle. Well, what do we have
here? We have a order block that has
already formed prior to the open of that
higher time frame candle. So, I can
anticipate that on the open of this
candle, I want price to trade lower, but
I don't want it to go take out this
high. So, that gives me an idea for my
stop loss and then also for my target
towards this low. Now, if you notice,
this is a 1 one. I ideally want to get a
1:2. So, then I'm just going to raise it
until I have that 1:2. I can set a limit
and then this would be somewhat of a
positional entry. As we let this print,
you can see my model prints out the
indicator. We have that reversal. We
have the projections, the liquidity. And
let's see what happens as now we are
trading this candle three. You can see
it's less than ideal. We have an
expansion somewhat of a consolidation,
but we do have price doing what? Taking
out a short-term high here and then
closing below this level. So, we could
now consider this a protected swing. So,
that would be that continuation where we
could anticipate this to expand lower.
Do we expand lower?
It takes a bit of time, but we do. So, I
just wanted to review this example. And
if we replay it,
you'll notice we do have a less than
ideal candle 2. You'll see how this
candle 2 is one of those that expands.
But let me talk about something
important here. It is still leaving this
short-term liquidity intact. If candle 2
would have expanded all the way to this
low, that's something I'm not ever
really going to trade. But with this
drawn liquidity still open, this is
where I can still look to trade that
continuation in candle three because I
have a spot for it to reach for. So here
we are in our next example. And if you
notice, we have had a reversal candle
here. And now it is met with another
reversal candle. So it's showing that we
failed this continuation lower. And if
we're reversing, then we can anticipate
a continuation higher. But where would I
want to see that continuation to as we
have closed back inside this previous
day's range is I'd want to see a new
high or that buyside liquidity. So with
this reversal daily candle then I could
anticipate a continuation in day three.
So going to the hourly time frame let's
see if we have the confirmation of this
reversal. So down here on the hourly
time frame you see we have a nice
V-shaped reversal. We have an SMT. So,
if we're looking for a continuation in
this day, we'd want to see price open,
make a low, form a protected swing to
trade higher. So, let's see if that
occurs. We get a nice slow shallow
retracement. And then here we get a
closure through the series of downclos
candles that made the low. So, this is
where I could look to get on side with a
position, my stop on the low, and trade
it higher. And you can see our 2R is
right with that liquidity there. How
does that work? We hit 2R. We also have
another SMT forming here with YM. Well,
what is another thing we could do here?
Well, this was looking to trade a
reversal on the lower time frame inside
that continuation day, but we could also
look to trade a lower time frame
continuation inside that reversal. So,
taking a look at this lower time frame
reversal here, you can see we were
trading this reversal, but I could also
look to trade a continuation off of
that. And then I'm trading a higher time
frame continuation with a lower time
frame continuation. And that is how I
prefer to do it. So if we get a closure
through the series of down close candles
here as we have this reversal and then
this would be the continuation order
block or the propulsion block then I
could have a trade that looks something
like this with the same target and I get
more risk-to-reward. We get the closure
through. We do. So then I could look to
get on side here. And how does that work
out? We hit RTP. So, there's lots of
ways you can go about this depending on
how strong your bias is. If you're
always trading a continuation day on the
higher time frame and you have a strong
bias, then you can get a bit more
aggressive on the lower time frames. If
you have less strong of a bias on a
continuation day, then it's better to
wait for that continuation on the lower
time frames as well. If you have a
higher time frame reversal day, right?
If you're trading candle 2 on a higher
time frame, then you might want to wait
for a continuation on the lower time
frame as you have less of that higher
time frame bias or confirmation. Now,
before we get into the next example,
let's go over a few other ways that I
could trade this reversal in here or
this intraday reversal using a
continuation. So, if you take a look at
the 4hour chart here as displayed on
this right side here, you see how we
have a nice candle to closure or a nice
reversal candle here. So, let's go see
if we could trade this using the 4hour
and 15minute model. So down here on the
15-minute chart, what is the first thing
we want to look for is we have a large
wick. So I'm not looking to try to trade
this reversal and we've moved open
higher first, then lower, then back up,
right? So I'm not expecting price to
expand within this given higher time
frame candle. I'm looking for the
continuation that follows. So I'm going
to want to let this candle close.
And this candle does close. Now, do we
have a change in the state of delivery
or that lower time frame confirmation?
We'll find the low. Have we closed over?
Not yet. So, we're going to need to wait
for it to close over.
And here we do get that closure over.
So, now we have confirmed this model and
I can anticipate price to trade higher
to these targets above. Now, if you
notice, we just took out a target. So,
we could get a retracement here. And if
we're going to continue higher, I want
to see price retrace, close over, and
then form a continuation higher. Now, if
we're going ahead and taking a look at
this, normally when I see price
consolidating, I'm not a big fan, right?
Cuz this would be a huge consolidation.
We're taking out the high and the
consolidation. Then we could trade this
back lower. But if we look inside here,
we have a smaller consolidation. So if
you see right here, we have a high, we
have a low. We swept out the low in this
consolidation. We formed a protected
swing here on the 15-minute
and then we formed another protected
swing here and then we are breaking out
of this range. So really, I'm going to
anticipate price to trade higher. If
price shows me that we are going to
reverse here, I'm uninterested. So I
want to see a shallow retracement, a
protected swing, and then to trade the
continuation. So let's see if that
occurs. We do have a fair value gap
right here as the point of interest.
So we do have a series of down closed
candles. Let's see if we can close over.
And we cannot. So we make a new low.
We're going to then track that new low.
Let's see if we can close over now.
And we do. So while still respecting
these protected swings over here, we
form a new protected swing. This is when
I can either look to take an entry on
this retest, my stop on the low,
targeting this liquidity here or the
highs, or I can look for a retest. So,
for instance, here, if I want to be able
to target this negative one or this
current high of day, maybe that is where
I'm going to use a smaller stop-loss or
looking for a retest to get on side with
this move. So, let's see what happens.
We do get that retest and then we trade
through our target and much higher. Now,
that's not the only way you could get on
side with this. If you remember, and if
you like the lower time frames, we could
take a look at the 30-inut chart here.
You see how the 30-inut after we formed
the protected swing here. Take a look.
We have a protected swing. We retrace.
If I didn't want to trade the
continuation on the 30 minute, I could
look for swing lows. So, if you notice,
we have a swing low here. We have a
swing low here. Each of these candles
following is something I could trade. So
I could trade this candle three closure
here long or I could trade this candle
two closure long here. So let's go and
take a look at this one, right? Because
we have a nice reversal candle here on
the 30 minute. So we could look at the
3minut. So what's the first thing we
want to do? Let this higher time frame
candle close. Tell us if it is a
reversal candle. It is. Do I have a
change in the state of delivery? No, not
yet. So we have to wait for that to
occur.
Now, we have formed a change in the
state of delivery and we have an
expansion. So, I'm not trying to trade
this at a high. Also, we just took out a
short-term target. So, I'm going to want
to wait for a retracement to then get on
side with a move higher. Ideally,
retrace into the fair value gap, close
over, and then trade it higher. And you
see how it's the same process over and
over with trading these continuations.
So, there we have a retracement. We go a
little bit deeper, but that is fine cuz
we're still respecting this area. So I
want to see if price can close over this
level here.
Now we are struggling to close over this
area and that is okay. We just want to
see if we can form a continuation.
And this is what I want to talk about
here. Right? If I'm going to want to
trade this, it's ideal if this closes
over quickly. But if you notice when we
go to go close over, we're forming a new
protected swing right in here. where
that is what I would anticipate. So if
we can get this closure over, let's see
what happens. We do I have a new
protected swing. Right? On this closure
over, we protect this swing as well.
Right? So now we have this as a
protected swing and this is a protected
swing. So I could take a target. So I
could take an entry there. We'll target
2 R on this and then see what happens.
Right? And there we go. And we hit R2R.
So you can see I'm trading a
continuation from the higher time frame,
a continuation on my intermediate time
frame, and also on this case a
continuation on my entry time frame. And
that is the way I prefer to trade is I'm
always trading continuations. But let's
get into another example. So here we are
with our next example and we are on RB
on the hourly chart and you can see the
daily candles on this right side here.
Now you can see we have a sweep and then
a closure back above that. But we do
have a little bit of an expansion here.
So, this is something I can still look
for longs as we're pretty close to this
objective here, but it sets up lower
expectations because we have expansion
and I could get a new phase of price.
So, with this, I'm going to demand a
continuation on the lower time frame.
This isn't a scenario where I try to
trade a reversal as I'm lacking that
super strong narrative. So, with this
closure, we have a change in the state
of delivery. We also have the SMT with
CL here. So, then what am I going to
wait for? I'm going to wait for that
same reversal candle on the lower time
frame as we let this continue. So you
can see we are just kind of
consolidating here within this range.
And what do I mean by that? We have one
candle here. Price has not taken out
either side of the range. Now we do take
out that side of the range. And what do
we have? We have a nice reversal candle.
So with that, let's drop down to our
lower time frame. We're on the hourly.
We can go ahead and go down to the
5minut chart. So you can see down here
on the 5-minute chart, we are getting
into New York where we start to get some
more volume. But let's see what happens.
We have a change in the state of
delivery. So what would we want to see?
I'm not trying to trade this reversal
here as I'm lacking the bias on the
higher time frame. I want to seek a
continuation. So what do we have? We
have price open reach down into this
change in the state of delivery
balancing out price. Do we get a
continuation? We do. As we close over
these down close candles, this is where
I could look to take a buy, my stop on
the current low, and then I could look
for 2 R here or to that buy side
liquidity or the projections above. So,
let's see what happens.
We almost get stopped out and then we
form a new continuation. And if you
notice, let's talk about this. If price
isn't expanding in candle 3, that's when
we're likely to get a candle 4
continuation if it is right. You can see
we're kind of forming a reversal candle
on candle 3 as well. Still closing
outside the range.
Let's see if we can get a continuation
in candle four here. So there we do take
out a short-term target. We want to see
a consolidation or a retracement for
continuation. We don't want to see price
form a bearish reversal, right? We don't
want to see that closure there. So let's
see what happens.
So not a great close, right? But we're
just going to stick to our plan. It's
more of a consolidation to me because
let's talk about this again. If price
was going to form that reversal, we'd
want to see a quick close below, right?
If we're trading this bearish, but since
it fails to do it and takes a long time,
I'm viewing this more as a
consolidation, right? So, it takes out
the low, then trades higher. See if we
can hit R2R here or 2.6R.
Just missed RTP and then we take it out.
We have a nice trade there. And you can
see we are trading a continuation on the
lower time frame and we're demanding
that because if we go back out to our
higher time frame here, yes, we have a
setup and it is a continuation. It's
just we've had expansion and then a
consolidation, right? Or a lower
probability. We want to see a reversal
candle that has a reversal, right? Not a
reversal and expansion, but you can
still trade it. It's just I need to
demand more on the lower time frames in
terms of confirmation. So here we are
with our next example and we have a nice
reversal candle. You can see price went
higher and then back lower closing near
its opening price. But did we have on
this closure a change in the state of
delivery? No. So we're waiting for the
closure through that. And now that we
have that the model will print. So this
is where I have a pretty decent bias to
this previous day's lows, right? Because
I can anticipate if price is going to
reverse here and form a continuation and
you can see we're forming a protected
swing in here. then the high of day
should be made and I can anticipate
price to expand lower. So let's see what
happens.
So there you can see we get an expansion
lower and this would be a candle for
trade. So if you want to check out that
video that is how you could trade that
candle but let's see if we can get a
retracement. So you can see we are
getting a retracement back up. So
expansion retracement. Let's see if we
can get another expansion lower. Want to
wait for a reversal candle. And so you
can see we do have a little bit of a
reversal candle, but that's not
something I really want to see, right? I
want to see something that has more of a
bearish closure. This is just a dogee.
So that is a nice reversal candle. You
can see how it's nice long wick on the
top end and it's closing back inside. So
with this we can drop down to the 5minut
as that is an hourly candle to closure.
So here we are and you can see what do
we have? We have price with a nice
V-shaped reversal, a consolidation, and
then I'd want to see if we can form a
continuation. Since we have swept out
this high in this consolidation, I want
to see if we can form a protected swing
here. Let's see what happens. So there
you can see the setup fails before
forming that continuation. And that is
an example of why I prefer those
continuations. If I was just to trade
the reversal, I would get stopped out
there. Let's see if we can still keep
this idea because the idea isn't
invalidated. I just need to have a new
setup. So, let's see. We have now a nice
candle to closure once again, right? So,
this would be a three drives pattern.
And if you notice, do we have the change
in the state of delivery yet? No. And
now, let me talk about this. This is one
that I'm usually not a fan of because
our sellside liquidity is at almost the
same point as our change in the state of
delivery. So, by the time we get our
change in the state of delivery, we're
taking out targets. Let's see if we do
form something. And you can see we do
form a model as we get this closure
below. But you see how we're also taking
out those targets there. So with an
expansion lower, I want to see the
phases of price. Do we get a retracement
into a fair value gap to then trade it
lower? Do we consolidate? And then I can
find a sweep and trade it lower or do we
reverse? In which case, I'm not really
interested. Right? And now we have a
nice V-shaped reversal. And you see how
this is forming a bullish setup. So
that's not really what we want to see.
So you can see we do get a weak close,
but this is not something I'm personally
going to try to trade cuz now we are
just consolidating. So if we mark out
our consolidation high and low, let's
see if we can take out the high to trade
it lower.
And so we do take out that high. I'm not
considering this a change in the state
of delivery because I'm looking for the
series of candles that made the high. So
let's see if we can get a change in the
state of delivery here to trade it
lower. And this would work because we're
still respecting the EQ of this original
candle 2 and forming a new candle 2 and
we can't get the closure. And so you can
see although we do get a change in the
state of delivery here, why is this
something I'm not considering? Because
it took so long to trade that really we
are just taking out consolidation lows,
right? So we're just in this big
consolidation still. So I'm going to
need a little more confirmation.
So there we go. We take out this high.
Now, it's the same idea, right? Do we
get a sweep and then a change in the
state of delivery? And at this point,
I'm not that interested. So, I'm going
to need more confirmation. So, either an
SMT with the change in the state of
delivery and a nice V-shaped reversal
cuz we do have these equal highs now.
And there you can see right here we have
that SMT, right, with the change in the
state delivery on the closure. So, this
is something where I could take a
reversal entry and be a bit more
aggressive due to the higher time frame
framework. Now, if I zoom out, where is
my target on this? I'm wanting to see
lower, right? That daily low, but I want
to use that sellside liquidity resting
below as a target. So, I want to see if
I can take a market entry. Can I get 2 R
to that low? And I can with my stop
above this. Now, why does this make
sense for a stop loss? Why not the high?
Well, if I'm at the high, I'm not
getting 2 R. So, I can go to this swing
point, this lower time frame swing
point. It's not a swing point on this
time frame. And the reason for that is
I'm expecting price to hold five of this
order block, right? this change in the
state delivery. So my stop is protected.
So what happens? Let's see.
And there we get that continuation
lower. So this is an example of because
my higher time frame bias is very
strong. I can look for a lower time
frame reversal as long as it meets my
expectations. And you can see if I was
waiting for a continuation, it doesn't
make sense to take a continuation in
here because where is my target? Right
there. Where am I going to put my stop
loss in here? Well, I need to allow for
price to trade higher if it wants to.
So, this is something I'd miss if I was
trading a continuation. And this is an
example of if you have a strong bias,
you can trade those lower time frame
reversals. A higher time frame
continuation paired with a lower time
frame reversal. So, this next example is
another of a higher time frame
continuation and then that is allowing
me to trade a lower time frame reversal.
So, if you notice here, we have price
expanding, right? So, we have expansion
lower, expansion up, that's forming a
reversal. So expansion once again a
consolidation consolidation is run out
right and you see how we have a nice
reversal candle here price is closing
green forming a nice wick on the lower
end here now this is an example of where
I wouldn't want to use 0.5 of the wick
let me give a lesson on that really
quick why would I want to use the whole
entire candles range and not.5 of the
wick well our whole thing is trading
expansion candles with a small wick so
if I want to trade a small wick I want
to see a shallow move than to trade it
higher if I'm using 0.5 of the wick.
Price comes all the way down here. Is
that respecting or forming a shallow
wick? No. So that's why I'm going to
look for 0.5 of this daily candles range
because it makes sense with this candle
type. So I want to see a shallow move to
trade it higher. So that is a very
strong bias. Let's go down to the hourly
time frame. So you can see here down on
the hourly time frame, we have that
candle to closure here. And you can see
this sets up lowquality conditions
following an expansion. This is a date
where I either want to have more
confirmation or avoid entirely. Here we
get the reversal. Still not a great
reversal day, but we do have the
confirmation. So in this next day, I'd
want to see price open, make a low, and
then can trade it higher. So let's go
ahead and play this out. So you can see
we have those targets right there. And
what are we doing? We have expansion
into what? A consolidation.
So marking out the consolidation range,
right? This is something I could
possibly trade here in London session as
we have a reversal candle. So that is
something I could look to trade higher
if I wanted to. For me, I trade New
York. So on this day, I was focused
here. Now, if you notice, what are we
doing? We're sweeping out the low in a
consolidation. This is where we would
want to get long, right? And on this
day, I have a lot of bias. This is where
I could trade this higher or anticipate
that. So, how could I actually trade the
reversal in here? Because I have a
strong bias on a higher time frame. So,
a higher time frame continuation. We're
in the continuation day. Trading a lower
time frame reversal. Let's drop down to
the 5minut. So, down here on the 5minut,
we're taking out that consolidation low.
And then I want to see am I forming a
reversal in here. Right?
And what do you notice on this close
here? We do have a very nice Vshape. And
this is where if I wanted to, I could
trade this lower time frame reversal
inside a higher time frame continuation
and look for it to trade to the highs.
So that would be it on the retest. Or if
I wanted to take the close, that would
also give me 2 R as well. So let's see
what happens.
There we go. And if you want to see how
I actually traded this, I actually
traded a 1 minute continuation in here.
And that is in a trade review video
posted, which I'll link in the
description. So let's get into one more
example. So here we are with our last
example here and we're going to be
blending candle 2, three, and four all
together. So if you notice here where I
have the daily chart and the monthly. If
you notice, we mark out the monthly
high. We are sweeping that high out. And
we have a nice V-shaped reversal up
here. Is that paired with a change in
the state of delivery? It is. Are we
respecting that change in the state of
delivery? We are. And if you notice, are
we forming a continuation while price
retraces back up into here? We have a
nice candle three closure which means I
can be looking for a candle for
continuation lower. So my candle four
here is in this case giving me my bias
to trade it lower where would be lower
sellside liquidity. So now I have a
whole idea for this month right and that
is why I posted on Twitter about my bias
for the start of this month. I would
expect price to trade lower here because
we're forming a protected swing right
prior to the open of the higher time
frame candle. So with this, let's drop
down to the hourly time frame and let's
see what happens. So if you notice here,
we do have that change in the state of
delivery from the high. The projections
also line up with that sellside
liquidity, which is nice to see. So
taking a look, let's go over something
real quick. We can also use the higher
time frame candles here to anticipate
where we want to see price respect. So
you can see we have the EQ. So we want
to see price respect that. But we also
have this higher time frame order block.
So marking that out, the opening price
right here.
And then the 0.5 is above that. So
really we have this little window in
price where we want to see be respected
right here. So I want to see the higher
time frame wick form in there. Well,
what is right there? We have this higher
time frame fair value gap. So I want to
see price trade into that fair value gap
and then can trade it lower.
So price does trade into that higher
time frame fair value gap there and so
we could look for a reversal on the
lower time frame here right because we
have a candle 2 closure we could trade
the lower time frames now if I'm in Asia
or the early parts of the day I'm trying
to stay on the higher time frames so at
least minimum 15 let's just see what
would happen on the hourly here on the
hourly you see how we form that
continuation now I can anticipate that
this wick should remain intact as we
trade lower throughout the day let's see
if we can get a retracement back up to
trade it lower. And there we do. And
let's see if a higher time frame gives a
better perspective here. So going to the
4 hour, we don't want to see this high
taken out. Can we form a swing point?
And there we do form a swing point.
Right now, this is a reversal candle and
a reversal expansion candle. So let's go
see what this actually looks like on the
lower time frame. Why could we be
looking for a reversal here? Well, we
know we don't want to see this high
taken out. So if that is the case, well
then a retracement back into this range.
I'm looking to sell and I want to use
previous candles highs and lows for
that. So either on the 4 hour or the 1
hour, right? And you can see the 1 hour
will also give a swing that we could
use. But for the sake of this example,
we're going to be using the 4 hour and
so we'd go to the 15-minut for the
model. Now down here on the 4 hour and
15 minute, you can see this is the high
we don't want taken. So a move back into
this range or into this previous range
I'm looking to sell. We have equal highs
right here and I'm looking to sell that.
Now, let's talk about this really quick.
Why wouldn't I be interested in this?
Well, you could, but look at how price
is forming. Open low. It's trading
higher. If you're trying to trade this
short, you're trying to fight that
reversal candle and it already has a
larger wick versus look at this candle.
It is sweeping its previous out and it
has a small wick. This small wick
supports expansion lower. Now, this is
where I can decide, do I want to trade
candle 2? as it is supported by this
small wick or do I want to wait for the
continuation in candle 3 and that really
comes down to your higher time frame
bias if you have a lot of bias you can
be more aggressive with these entries
and I could look to trade this reversal
right here instead of the continuation
so let's see what happens
and there you can see we have SMT on the
high we have the change in state
delivery a nice V-shaped reversal and
you can tell that because it is paired
with an inversion here but with that
that's where I could look to trade this
reversal if I have a higher time frame
bias that aligns with it. There I could
look for an entry and I'm expecting if
price is to trend lower or we make a low
high high lower lower low high lower low
I could look for price to trade to this
low. So 4R or if we are going to have an
expansion day I can really hold to the
end of the daily candle but let's see
what happens there we get an expansion.
So expansion can we form a retracement?
Well, let's see. You can see we can't
close over there to form the retracement
and then we get a move higher. Now, if
I'm taking the reversal, I'm I just have
to trust this, right? I can sure take
off at 2 R if it hits it. It didn't in
this case, but if I'm waiting for the
continuation, there is no entry yet. So,
price returns to our entry. And what do
we notice here? We are forming a
continuation. Price does trade higher.
This looks like an expansion, but it's
met with expansion. So that's forming a
wick on a slightly higher time frame. We
now have a protected swing. This is
where I could look for a continuation.
Right now, if I still want to target the
same area, I'm going to have to put my
stop around this area. And why could
that make sense? Well, we have nice
bulky bodies using.5 of that. It's above
that, right? Or if I'm going to use a
true protected swing, then I'm going to
need to get a little more for 2. Let's
see what happens.
There is another continuation. Let's say
you missed this one. We have another
continuation here. Look to take an
entry. I stopped there. Can I get two R
out of this right there? Let's see.
Oh, that one gets stopped out. We have
SMT, right? So, this continuation may
not work, right? Or we have SMT with YM.
So, YM would be the better short
opportunity there. But we go and trade
it lower. So, two out of three of those
trades would have worked. And you'll see
why I prefer to trade within candle 3,
right? I like to trade that first
continuation instead of the further
continuations because I feel like I'm
chasing. But where does this eventually
go to? If you remember, if we're back
out on the hourly time frame, we want to
see this return to that daily sellside.
And you can see it does go and hit that.
So, if that's something I'm going to
hold, that's where you can get those
really insane risk-to-reward trades. But
for the sake of this, that is how I
would approach it. So, I hope you
enjoyed this video. I hope with the
candle 2 video and the candle 4 video,
you now understand each candle within my
fractal model. So, candle 2, the
reversal candle, candle 3, the
continuation, or it can be a reversal
candle, and candle 4, which is always a
continuation within my model. Now, if
you have any questions, be sure to leave
them in the comment section below. And
with that, I hope you guys have a good
one. See you.